Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we're here
talking about some special foods today.
That's right, today we're
going to talk about sea food,
so everything that comes
from the sea that we eat.
That's right, so we're in a
restaurant and we're going to
hear about the different
options this restaurant offers.
Let's take a listen to the dialogue.
This is such a nice
restaurant, I feel so classy.
Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but
they serve the best sea food in town.
May I take your order?
Yes, I would like some
marinated grilled shrimp
for starters, and I'll
also have the lobster.
Excellent choice, sir, and for you, madam?
I would like to bake oysters
and the seafood platter.
Very good, madam.
That seafood platter sounds good.
Excuse me, what does the platter have?
It's a great combination
of clams, scallops,
mussels, calamari, and
fillet of salmon and tuna.
It comes with a side of
butter sauce and french fries.
That sounds great, cancel the lobster
and give me one of the same, please.
Very well, sir, anything to drink?
Can we get a bottle of your
house white wine, please?
Superb choice, I will be
back shortly with the wine.
All right, we're back, so today we're going
to take a look at a lot of vocab, so we're
going to have two parts of language
takeaway, and let's start with the first one.
Language takeaway.
Now, in language
takeaway part one, today we
have a number of really
important and useful adjectives.
The first one is classy.
That's right, so we're
going to a nice restaurant,
and so you feel like
you're in a classy place.
Now, a classy place
is a nice place, you
might be expected to dress
nicely, it might be a little bit fancy.
Exactly, so classy is kind of a
synonym of fancy or luxurious.
Right, so if you're going
on a date with someone,
it might be a good idea
to go to a classy restaurant.
That's right, but
usually if a restaurant is
classy, it also means
that it's a little bit pricey.
Okay, so something that is pricey is
expensive, and seafood is famous in America.
For being very pricey.
That's right, so something that is pricey
means that it's a little bit expensive.
Now, going to the
food that we're going to
get today, we had a
couple of different ways
of describing how the
food was prepared, so
for example, the first one
is marinated grilled shrimp.
All right, now something
that is marinated
is covered in a sauce or
a liquid before it's cooked.
All right, so you can
have maybe a regular
steak, but you can also
have a marinated steak
which would be marinated in some
kind of flavor, like garlic or yogurt.
That's right, so usually
you leave it in maybe
some sauce, like garlic
sauce for a couple
of hours or a couple of
minutes before you cook it.
Now, when we cook it, there are
different ways of cooking things.
In this case, we're having grilled shrimp.
All right, now grilled is different from
fried, fried we do in a pan with some oil,
but a grill, usually
there's no pan, no oil,
there's just a grill,
so grill, grilled.
Grill is the tool that we use.
Grilled food tends
to be quite healthy,
there's very little
oil, it's a bit more dry,
and oftentimes we do grilling
outside because there's lots of smoke.
That's right, because usually you have like
maybe a barbecue and you have some charcoal
in there or some wood, and that's
what you use to cook the food with.
Yeah, and grilled food is very
easy to notice because there are
usually black lines on top and
bottom, that's from the grill.
That's right, so we
ordered marinated grilled
shrimp for starters,
so what is a starter?
Well, think about the word starter, start.
Now, a starter is something you eat at
the start of your meal, at the beginning.
You eat it before you eat the main course.
All right, so it's also
known as an appetizer.
That's right, starters
and appetizers are the
same thing, and these
are small, things you
eat before you start to eat your
main meal, so they're not very filling.
Mm-hmm, okay, so yeah,
it'll be something small, like a
soup, or maybe like in this
case, a marinated grilled shrimp.
Yes.
All right, so great vocab
there, why don't we
review that part, and
we'll be back in a bit.
This is such a nice
restaurant, I feel so classy.
Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but
they serve the best seafood in town.
May I take your order?
Yes, I would like some
marinated grilled shrimp
for starters, and I'll
also have the lobster.
Excellent choice, sir, and for you, madam?
I would like the baked
oysters and the seafood platter.
Very good, madam.
That seafood platter sounds good.
Excuse me, what does the platter have?
It's a great combination
of clams, scallops,
mussels, calamari, and
fillet of salmon and tuna.
It comes with a side of
butter sauce and french fries.
That sounds great.
Cancel the lobster and give
me one of the same, please.
Very well, sir.
Anything to drink?
Can we get a bottle of your
house white wine, please?
Superb choice, I will be
back shortly with the wine.
All right, so now let's take
a look at all of the exquisite
types of seafood that we have
here on language takeaway part two.
All right, now the
first thing we have in
language takeaway part two is a
very distinctive animal from the ocean.
It's bright red, and it has two claws.
Right, we're talking about a lobster.
Now lobsters, you don't find everywhere, in
fact there are some parts of America where
they're very famous for
their lobster, like Maine.
Now these are animals that
are hard on the outside, and soft
and white on the inside, and
they're quite difficult to eat.
That's right.
So they look kind of
like crabs because they
also have the claws and everything,
but they're a lot longer, right?
That's right, a crab
is round and a lobster
is long, and lobsters are also
famous for one part for their tails.
Right, the tails are full of meat.
They're very delicate, very delicious.
Okay, so we're having some lobster,
and we also ordered some baked oysters.
Now oysters are another kind of
thing that comes from the ocean.
They come in a shell,
and you might hear about
oysters because some
people, some restaurants
like to have an oyster bar where
they serve raw oysters over ice.
That's right.
So they look like big rocks, basically, and
when you open them inside, you have meat.
And actually, I think you
get pearls from oysters, right?
That's right.
So these two are special.
They have a nice relationship, the pearl
forms inside a grows inside of the oyster.
Very good.
So now we've taken a
look at some oysters and
talking about these
things that have shells.
We also have clams.
Now while oysters
are big and sometimes
quite shiny, clams are
smaller, usually white
or gray, and they
have lines on them, and
their shells that you open up
and you eat the meat from inside.
Right, so I guess if
you've ever been on the
beach and you're collecting little sea
shells, usually those are kind of like clams.
That's right.
They're quite small.
They can be about the size of
an American quarter, 25 cents.
Okay.
So now in this seafood platter
that we're ordering, we have clams.
We have scallops.
Ooh, scallops are one of
my favorite kinds of seafood.
They're quite soft and chewy,
and they're usually white, okay.
And then we have some mussels also.
Now mussels are much different looking.
They're also in shells, but they're
long, and the shells are black.
That's right.
So clams are kind of small and round.
The oysters are pretty
big and look like rocks.
Mussels on the other
hand are long and black.
And when you open them
inside, they're shiny also.
They're orange on the inside or yellow.
And so they're quite interesting looking.
But they're also very famous for the French
or Belgian rather, the Belgian dish mooled
fruit, which is a nice
specialty, all right?
And lastly, we are also having
some calamari in this seafood platter.
Oh, this is another one of my favorites.
Now calamari is a kind of
food, but the animal is the squid.
Okay.
So why is it called calamari?
Well, calamari, I believe, comes
from the Italian word, calamari.
Calamari means that it's squid that's
been cooked so that people can eat it.
Okay.
So basically, calamari and
squid are the same thing.
They are the same animal, but
calamari means that it's prepared to eat.
Yes.
And usually it's fried.
So when squid is fried,
it becomes hard, chewy.
And that's what calamari tastes like.
It's quite chewy.
All right.
Great stuff.
So why don't we review everything
one last time with this exquisite lesson?
This is such a nice restaurant.
I feel so classy.
Yeah, it's a little bit pricey, but
they serve the best seafood in town.
May I take your order?
Yes, I would like some
marinated grilled shrimp
for starters, and I'll
also have the lobster.
Excellent choice, sir.
And for you, madam?
I would like the baked
oysters and the seafood platter.
Very good, madam.
That seafood platter sounds good.
Excuse me.
What does the platter have?
It's a great combination
of clams, scallops,
mussels, calamari, and
fillet of salmon and tuna.
It comes with a side of
butter sauce and french fries.
That sounds great.
Can't put a lobster and give
me one of the same, please.
Very well, sir.
Anything to drink?
Can we get a bottle of your
house-wide wine, please?
Superb choice.
I will be back shortly with the wine.
All right, so seafood,
we said, usually has
the connotation of
being a little bit pricey.
Why do you think that is?
I think it's pricey because the best
seafood doesn't come from seafood farms.
It comes from people who go in boats
and they collect the seafood in nets.
And also, there are fewer and fewer places
now in America where you can find this kind
of food because some places
have experienced overfishing.
Too many people are trying the fish.
And also, some places just don't have
the right climate for certain animals.
Right.
People in the United
States, you do have,
well, the whole country
is covered in the West
Coast by the Pacific Ocean, the
East Coast, you have the Atlantic.
So obviously, you do
have some coast, but if
you're in the middle
of the United States,
it's partly hard to get seafood,
so I imagine it's very expensive.
It can be very, very expensive,
so oftentimes we get lake food.
It's different kind of fish,
but we don't have lobsters.
But you'll find that in
the West, you get very
good salmon because
Alaska in the Northwest
is very famous for
salmon from the Pacific.
And in the East, it's very famous for
lobster and crab, which are delicious.
Now, even though you
have its famous for lobster
and crab, it's still relatively
expensive compared to other dishes.
For example, I think a lobster, how
much would a lobster dinner cost?
A lobster dinner could cost you $150.
Right, and you're getting
almost the same amount
of meat as maybe having
a steak that would be $20.
Yeah, less meat.
But we have more cows
than we have lobsters,
and also lobsters are famous
for being pretty expensive.
It's a very fancy meal to have lobster.
So it's very interesting, and actually some
countries, so it's very interesting, but
some countries seafood
is very, very inexpensive.
Some communities
or some countries are
communities that fish or
have, for example, shrimp farms.
It's very inexpensive, so it's such a treat
to be able to go there and have seafood all
you want and not have
to spend $300 on a meal.
It is indeed, and it's
really nice to be able
to get these big
prawns, these big shrimp
or lobsters and eat them
without worrying about the price.
But I'm curious, in your
country, do you have
seafood, and if so, what kind is it
cheap is it expensive, is it pricey?
Let us know where our
website is www.EnglishPod.com.
All right, we'll see you guys there.